Now here's a very common situation that you may come across.
现在，您可能会遇到一种非常常见的情况。
You want to do something with a friend but you don't really care what exactly you do.
你想和朋友一起做某事，但你并不真正关心你到底做了什么。
For example you're going to go out to dinner but where you eat is not important to you right.
例如，你要出去吃晚饭，但你在哪里吃饭对你来说并不重要。
You're a bit apathetic toward where you're going to go out to eat and you want your friend to choose.
你对出去吃饭的地方有点冷漠，你想让你的朋友选择。
You want them to decide OK you don't care.
你希望他们决定好，你不在乎。
You could say I don't care.
你可以说我不在乎。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
But there are a couple of specific expressions that we can use here that can be used to push decisions
但是我们可以在这里使用一些特定的表达式来推动决策
to other people.
给其他人。
OK.
好的。
So let's look at those and these are pretty simple.
所以让我们看看这些，这些都非常简单。
One friend says Do you want to go out to eat later.
一位朋友说，你以后要出去吃饭吗？
Yeah sure that sounds fun.
是的，这听起来很有趣。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Any ideas any ideas and it's your call.
任何想法任何想法，这是你的电话。
It's your call see a l l call.
这是你的电话，请看我的电话。
Yes.
是的。
This call means decision.
这个呼召意味着决定。
It's your decision.
这是你的决定。
I'm taking my option to give a decision or to decide I'm giving it to you and whatever you say is what
我正在选择做出决定或决定我把它给你，不管你说什么
we will do.
我们会做的。
So you say let's eat Thai food and I say OK OK I don't care.
所以你说让我们吃泰国菜，我说好吧好吧我不在乎。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
It's your call.
这是你的电话。
It's your call and you can use it for lots of other social situations where you want other people to
这是您的电话，您可以将它用于您希望其他人的许多其他社交场合
decide.
决定。
It's your call.
这是你的电话。
Whatever.
任何。
Maybe you're going on a vacation and you want to choose where to go on vacation.
也许你要去度假，你想选择去哪里度假。
Lots of different situations you can use it anywhere.
很多不同的情况，你可以在任何地方使用它。
Also you can use up to you to you know up to you could be about a responsibility.
你也可以用你自己知道你可能是一个责任。
It's up to you to make sure that everyone is safe.
确保每个人的安全都取决于您。
OK.
好的。
That's your responsibility.
那是你的责任。
So that's OK.
所以没关系。
But up to you can also mean I'm lifting up the decision and allowing you sort of offering it to you
但由你决定也可能意味着我正在提升决定并允许你将其提供给你
to choose up to you.
由您选择。
I'm holding it here and you can decide this or this.
我把它放在这里，你可以决定这个或这个。
Where do you want to go for dinner.
你想去哪里吃晚饭。
Up to you.
由你决定。
OK.
好的。
You left it up to me to decide where we were going to go on our vacation and I decided that we would
你让我来决定我们要去哪里度假，我决定我们会
go on a skiing trip.
去滑雪旅行。
And now you're all complaining to me about choosing to go on a ski trip.
现在你们都在向我抱怨选择去滑雪旅行。
So then why did you say it's up to me if you didn't really mean it.
那么，如果你不是真心的，那你为什么说这取决于我。
If it's really up to me then you can't complain.
如果这真的取决于我，那么你不能抱怨。
OK.
好的。
So sometimes when people say it's up to you it's not it's not really what they feel.
所以有时当人们说这取决于你时，这并不是他们真正的感受。
And then later when someone else makes the decision they complain to common common situation that I
然后当其他人做出决定时，他们会抱怨我的常见情况
face.
脸。
OK.
好的。
So that's another way to push a decision on others.
因此，这是将决定强加于他人的另一种方式。
And we can also say here whatever whatever.
我们也可以在这里随便说。
Where do you want to eat whatever.
想去哪里吃什么都行。
Sort of like saying you choose and you could add whatever is fine whatever is fine whatever is ok whatever
有点像说你选择，你可以添加任何好的任何好的任何可以的任何东西
is good with me could also say good with me.
对我很好也可以说对我很好。
So these are three very common expressions we can use in many many many many many situations to express
所以这是三个非常常见的表达方式，我们可以在很多很多很多情况下使用来表达
the idea of I don't want to decide I'm giving you the decision.
我不想决定的想法我给你决定。
Basically that's what these mean.
基本上就是这些意思。
OK.
好的。